Guide to the Ernest William Schoder papers, [ca.1903-1968].
Schoder, Ernest William papers, [ca.1903-1968].
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ernest William Schoder papers, [ca.1903-1968].
16-4-1156
Ernest William Schoder, 1879-1968
16 cubic ft.
Notes, lectures, exams, printed material, texts, correspondence, diaries, reports, blueprints, graphs, charts, photographs, and glass negatives.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes notes, lectures, lab notes, exams, printed matter, hydraulics texts, and other course material; correspondence; diaries; reports; blueprints; graphs; charts; test data; photographs; glass negatives; and other papers related to Schoder's career as a professor of civil engineering.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of experimental hydraulics, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes notes, lectures, lab notes, exams, printed matter, hydraulics texts, and other course material; correspondence; diaries; reports; blueprints; graphs; charts; test data; photographs; glass negatives; and other papers related to Schoder's career as a professor of civil engineering.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schoder, Ernest William, 1879-1968; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Civil engineering.; Hydraulics.; Hydraulics--Research.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Charts.; Negatives.; Graphs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Courses: Notes, Lectures, Lab Notes, Exams, Hydraulics Text (mimeo sheets) (Box 1)
- Courses, Printed Matter (Box 2)
- Courses, Printed Matter (Box 3)
- Courses, Printed Matter (Box 4)
- Thesis Lab Notes & Computations, Letterbox, Letterpress Book (Box 5)
- Courses (Box 6)
- 2nd and 3rd edition Hydraulics Text (Schoder & Dawson), Correspondence and Notes, Reports (Box 7)
- Hydraulics Text, Notebooks (Box 8)
- Cornell, Seattle Security Company; Reports, Correspondence, Printed Matter (Box 9)
- Courses, Test Data (Box 10)
- Hydraulics Text, Letterbox, Printed Matter (Box 11)
- Photographs, Glass Negatives, Printed Matter (Box 12)
- Certificates, Correspondence, Cards, Clippings, Printed Matter (Box 13)
- Courses, Notebooks, Field Notes (Box 14)
- Correspondence, Alpha file A-Z, 1910-1961 (Box 15)
- Subjects, Alpha file A-Z, 1913-1940 (Box 16)
- Springfield Waterworks Little River Supply, Contract No. 1, Intake Dam and Tunnel Consulting Engineers, Hazen & Whipple - blueprints, 1907 (Folder 1)
- New York State Barge Canal - series of blueprints, dams, tunnels, lockgates, sluice gates, etc., circa 1907-1912 (Folder 1-2)
- Temperature, rainfall run-off at Ithaca Fall Creek Watershed - blueprints, and reports, 1879-1904 (Folder 2)
- Blueprints and specifications of house for the Filtration Plant, Clarence A. Martin, Architect, 1903 (Folder 2)
- Cascadilla Park Project - blueprint, ca., 1909 (Folder 2)
- Hydraulic Laboratory - blueprints, circa 1914, 1943 (Folder 2)
- Section of S.H. Hammondsport-Branchport, PT.2, F.A. Dempster & Losey, P.E. & L.S., Dyeline print, 1939 (Folder 2)
- Holland Patent, New York, blueprints (maps and plans), ca., 1911 (Folder 2)
- Bridges at Elmira, N.Y. - blueprints, ca., 1919 (Folder 2)
- Dodge-Lewis Controversy, blueprints and notes, 1920 (Folder 2)
- Map of University Place known as McGraw Fiske property by C.L. Crandall, 1910 (Folder 2)
- Title Investigation of New York Harbor - map and blueprints, 1919 (Folder 2-3)
- Willard Way Encroachment - blueprints, reports, etc., ca., 1910-1925 (Folder 2-3)
- New York Court of Claims, Case No. 2365A - Oneida Lake, Oneida River, and Caughdenoy Eel Weirs. Blueprints and charts, 1917 (Folder 3)
- Movie Film
  - Chenango River Model (Floats - mostly velocity studies), (8 4" reels), 1937-1938
  - Conowinga Dam, (1 4" reel), 1937
  - Strain Gage on concrete beams in fatigue tests, (1 4" reel), 1935
  - Concrete beams - Berry Strain gage, reversal of stress, (1 4" reel), 1931
  - Hippos, Destruction of French Fleet by British, and Collapse of Tacoma Narrows Bridge, (1 7" reel), 1940
  - Football Parade, (10 7" reels), 1939-1943, 1945-1949
  - Football - Dartmouth-Cornell, (1 7" reel), Nov. 15, 1930
  - Football - Cornell-Princeton, (1 7" reel), Oct. 19, 1929
  - Football - Cornell-Hobart, (1 3" reel), Nov. 8, 1930
  - Football - Hampden Sidney-Cornell, (1 4" reel), Oct. 12, 1929
  - Football - Clarkson Tech.-Cornell and Hampden-Sidney, (1 4" reel), Sept. 28, 1929, Oct. 12, 1929
  - Girl Scouts, July 20, (1 7" reel), 1929
  - Rowing (?) Intercollegiate Freshmen Varsity, Syracuse (?) (1 7" reel), 1928
  - No title, tins labelled 1, 2, 3, 4 (" reel)
  - (4 7" reels)